## **KELVIN NGUYEN**

17 Rafael street, MELBOURNE, VIC

Mobile: (+61) 447-359-073 Email: duchung97dl@gmail.com Website: kelvinnguyen97.com Blog: https://dev.to/kelvin0712

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelvin-nguyen-317359148

# **SUMMARY**

A software engineer with strong experience in Front-end Development and Back-end Development. Good knowledge of Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Database Design, Design Patterns. Strong written and verbal communication.

I value lifelong learning, a quick learner, a team player, problem solving lover and always up to learning new things and improving my current skill set.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages:
  - JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
  - HTML5, CSS4
- Frameworks/Platforms:
  - ReactJS, NodeJS
  - Babel, Webpack
  - REST API or GraphQL API
  - Express.js
- Others:
  - Agile and Scrum development process, Docker

## Database Management Systems:

- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Version control:
  - Git

## **WORK HISTORY**

## Full-stack developer (1/2020 to present)

#### **Bookwell**

## Responsivities:

- Developing new and customization of the existing features for the high-profile web application using ReactJS.
- Develop and fix the application's defect base on requirements.
- Refactoring old components to use new cutting-edge technologies
- Debug code and profile system performance to troubleshoot functional and nonfunctional issues

## Software engineer intern (11/2019 to 12/2019)

## Sleeping duck

#### Responsibilities:

- Capturing the best development practices in a way of common condign standards team
  of 4 developers that helped to decrease code complexity and improve maintainability
  of the shared libraries and components.
- Performing unit & load testing for the high-profile customers-facing portal applying knowledge of RSpec eliminating system's failure rate by 79%.

## **PROJECTS**

## Project: Recipe Application (7/2019 to 8/2019)

- **Project Description:** Using pure JavaScript ES6 to fetch and manipulate data from an open API. This application allows users to search for recipe that they want to. Moreover, users can also save the recipe they like and add ingredients to the shopping list.
- Link: https://kelvin0712.github.io/Recipe\_app/

## **Project: React Burger (1/2019 to 3/2019)**

- Project Description: Using React for Front-End development and store information in Firebase. A
  system that allows users create their own burger and purchase it after creating. I learned React by myself
  through developing this burger app.
- Link: https://kelvin0712.github.io/react\_burger/

# **VOLUNTEER WORKS & EXTRA ACTIVITIES**

## Hacker at GovHack Queensland (2019)

Working in a team of 6 to build a webpage to help start-ups to find out about the demographic of a certain area on the map by using open APIs from the Queensland government, HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript, deployed on AWS.

Link: https://ricedatahack.s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/testMap.html

## **EDUCATION**

2017 - 2019 Bachelor of Information of Technology, The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.

## REFEREES

## Ha (Harry) Nguyen

Full-stack developer

sonhanguyen@outlook.com